Preliminary Inventory to the Joanna Szczesna Collection, 1970-1986
Hoover Institution Archives
Joanna Szczesna Collection,
1970-1986
93054
Szczesna, Joanna
21 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box 9.67 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, bulletins, serial issues, pamphlets, and leaflets, relating to political, economic, and human rights conditions in Poland, Solidarnosc and other oppositional organizations, political prisoners, and official and oppositional press and radio broadcasting.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Civil rights--Poland; Dissenters--Poland; Labor movement--Poland; Labor unions--Poland; Mass media--Poland; Political prisoners--Poland; Poland; Poland--Economic conditions--1981-1990; Poland--Politics and government--1980-1989; NSZZ "Solidarnosc" (Labor organization)
Container List
- 1984-1985 elections (Box 1.)
- Biuletyn Informacyjny materials (Box 2.)
- Miscellaneous papers on the pre-Solidarity opposition and on the Catholic Church (Box 3.)
- Miscellaneous Solidarity papers, 1980-1981 (Box 4.-6.)
- Political trials of Solidarity activists, internment camps, prisons, etc. (Box 7.-8.)
- Solidarity graphics, leaflets (Box 9.)
- Students, workers, farmers (Box 10.)
- Surveys of official press; Radio Solidarity; Polish radio stations abroad (Box 11.)
- Surveys, reports, and other Solidarity materials (Box 12.-13.)
- Surveys, reports, and other Solidarity materials, 1982-1983 (Box 14.)
- Surveys, reports, and other Solidarity materials, 1982-1986 (Box 15.)
- Tygodnik Mazowsze materials (Box 16.-18.)
- Tygodnik Mazowsze materials, 1985 (Box 19.)
- Underground poetry and prose; Solidarity abroad (Box 20.)
- Miscellaneous papers, leaflets, posters (i.a. police forgeries,) 1980-1981 (Box 21.)
- Tygodnik Mazowsze catalogue of underground Solidarity press (Box 22.)